

ZARQA REHMAN

CONTACT

+91 9873743947



zarqarehman04@gmail.com



Delhi, India 🙎



SOFTWARES

- AutoCAD
- Revit
- SketchUp Lumion
- Photoshop •••• MS Office Suite
- Enscape

SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Time Management
- Leadership
- Verbal & Written communication

CERTIFICATIONS

• Karwaan's SketchUp - Intermediate Level

••••

••••

••••

....

- Culturally Built Environment IIT Roorkee
- Vulnerability Scale of India SPA Delhi
- LOMOS Revit + Lumion + Photoshop

LANGUAGE

English

••••

Hindi

Urdu

•••• ••••

SOCIAL MEDIA

- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/zarga-rehman-7113a8215
- f https://www.facebook.com/zarqa.rehman
- nttps://instagram.com/zarqaaaa? utm_medium=copy_link

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Hi! I'm Zarqa Rehman, a 4th year student at Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University for Women, Delhi majoring in architecture. This folio comprises series of selected works which gives an insight of my architectural journey until now.

The projects depicted here features skills like conceptual brainstorming and design ideation and development, selected plans, elevations, sections and details, 3D views and renders.

Apart from this, I am an articulate writer, and have published five articles on digital platform. Also, I have been doing fashion and event photography.

In future, I aim to further broaden my architectural horizons and reflect it in my work. To me architecture has been amalgamation of art and ideation, which mirrors in the society.

I want to consistently work towards my passion for architecture, and want to work closely with the people on ground for the upliftment of the society.

EDUCATION

Laxman Public School, Hauz Khas, New Delhi

 Class 10th Class 12th • Year: 2016 Year: 2018 • CGPA: 9.6 Percentage: 78%

Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University For Women, Kashmere Gate, Delhi

- Bachelor's of Architecture
- Year: 2019-2024 • SGPA: 8.00

EXPERIENCE

Rethinking The Future

 Architectural Journalism Intern October 2021 - November 2021

Wrote articles on various topics related to architecture and allied fields. Five of the articles written were also published on the website of Rethinking The Future (eduwick.com)

Amrit Sarovar Mahotsav - Rejuvenation of water bodies of India

 Architectural Intern June 2022 - August 2022

Under AICTE, Govt. of India and Ministry of Urban Affairs and Housing, worked on rejuvenation and restoration of water bodies of Delhi in heritage setting. Proposals were made on urban design and urban planning methodology.

Axiom India

- Architectural Intern
- January 2023 April 2023

Worked on various residential projects, and architectural projects, enhancing my knowledge and skills on the subject

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

• 7th Sem Redevelopment of Government Housing, R.K Puram Sector 5, Delhi

• **6th Sem** *Campus Design*

PRADAN Campus, Itarsi, Madhya Pradesh

• 5th Sem Hospital Design

Noida, Uttar Pradesh

• 4th Sem Co-educational Student Accommodation

Kashmere Gate. Delhi

• 3rd Sem Pre-Primary School

Delhi

• **2nd Sem** Artisan's House

Garli, Himachal Pradesh

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- President of the Photography Club of IGDTUW (Sept 2021-Dec 22)
- Currently the President of Unnat Bharat Abhiyan, a flagship program of Ministry of Urban Affairs & Housing, Govt. of
- Mentor at Desh Ke Mentor, a Delhi Government initiative (Phase 2 March - August 2022)
- Participated at Annual NASA Convention 2022
- · Participated in Lift Car Design Competition by Schindler
- Participated in Writing Architecture Trophy (NASA India 2020)

WORKSHOPS

2020 Urban Spaces by Goethe Institute Architalks by Architects: A talk series by renowned architects

2022 Parametric Facades and Fenestrations | Annual NASA Convention Ethos: Walk For A Cause | Annual NASA Convention **Documentation**

Arab Ki Sarai Baoli, Delhi

Shamsi Talaab, Mehrauli, Delhi (top 10 entries all over India) Ahilya Bai Ghat, Maheshwar, Madhya Pradesh